{
    "id": "da5e28a8c870418b99468c4c04d826a2",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The government …………………….. a consumer protection agency last month.",
            "description": "To simply state that something happened sometime ago, we use the simple past.",
            "answers": [
                "institutes",
                "instituted",
                "has instituted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d7fa19ca4cab49058fab53931ef24f3c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The university ……………………… to establish an institute for Asian studies.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "plans",
                "will plan",
                "has planned"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "19691ce28f9d491ca49784251d680cda"
        },
        {
            "question": "The institution of slavery ………………………… once widespread.",
            "description": "Use the simple past for finished past events. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1335ca08d195478dbaca48efdb33e094"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………… that she heard someone in the house.",
            "description": "When one verb is in the past tense, the other verbs too will most probably be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "insists",
                "insisted",
                "has insisted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ca4a614c773046789290e0195efe1c91"
        },
        {
            "question": "The auditor …………………………. the books every month.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about routines, habits, facts etc.",
            "answers": [
                "inspects",
                "is inspecting",
                "had inspected"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "029dd86fbeb64ce5a1cab86305006491"
        },
        {
            "question": "A fair and kind employer …………………………. loyalty.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about facts and general truths.",
            "answers": [
                "has inspired",
                "inspires",
                "inspired"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ae3d2097dd5c406bb2c166a027f43ab4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Everyone ……………………………. as an individual.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "should recognize",
                "should be recognized"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "0f36eca9936440c6b5b392a3913f43ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "When we got talking I found out that we …………………………. at school together twenty-five years before.",
            "description": "Before is often used with a past perfect to count back from a past moment.",
            "answers": [
                "were",
                "have been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "601621db56624eb5b4d330ff5638a3d5"
        },
        {
            "question": "My mom has a strange accent. She almost ………………………… foreign.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has sounded",
                "sounds",
                "sounded"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4d1b8b444ae2488fb515368170d133cb"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you before I …………………….",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "came",
                "come",
                "will come"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "49a021f995d64901b15a2ddcd41c3344"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. school when he was twelve.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has left",
                "left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "48e4e212b1594584ac7f51ca2d1a1b4c"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………………. me you were not coming.",
            "description": "Could have + past participle is used to criticize people for not doing things in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "could tell",
                "could have told"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b219f70f6b8844e18041197e4d02ee0a"
        }
    ]
}